Max Weber
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Max Weber papers
1902-2008
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Weber, Max
11.3 linear feet
The papers of New York painter and sculptor Max Weber measure 11.3 linear feet and date from 1902-2008. The collection documents Weber's career as an artist through scattered biographical material; correspondence with artists, curators, universities, arts organizations, and others; exhibition and gallery files; personal business records; writings by Weber and others; exhibition catalogs, news clippings, and other printed material; photographs of Weber, exhibitions, and works of art; and audio and film recordings. Also included are records maintained by Joy Weber on the exhibition and sale of Weber's work after his death.
Provenance
Material was lent for microfilming in 1959 by Max Weber and in 1969 by Mrs. Max Weber and daughter, Joy Weber. The bulk of the microfilmed material and additional papers were donated in 2011 by Joy Weber.
Separated Material
Material lent for microfilming in 1959 and 1969 which was not included in the 2011 donation is available on microfilm reels NY59-6 to NY59-10, N69-82 to N69-88, and N69-112.
Related Material
Also found at the Archives of American Art is an Allen L. Wetmore letter from Max Weber, April 15, 1946.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment. Use of archival audiovisual recordings with no duplicate access copy requires advance notice.
Biographical Note
Max Weber (1881-1961) was a painter and sculptor in New York City.
Weber was born in Bialystok, Russia. When he was ten years old his family moved to Brooklyn, New York. From 1898 to 1900 he attended Pratt Institute and studied theory and practice of design under Arthur Wesley Dow. After graduating he briefly taught drawing in Lynchburg, Virginia, and Duluth, Minnesota. In 1905 he moved to Paris to attend the Académie Julian, studying under Jean-Paul Laurens, and later attended classes at the Académie Colarossi and Académie de la Grande Chaumiere. In 1907 he attended Henri Matisse's studio class. The influence of Matisse and friend Henri Rousseau transformed Weber's painting style to include elements of cubism and fauvism.
Weber returned to New York in 1909, and over the next few years he frequently exhibited at Alfred Stieglitz's gallery 291. Initially his work was panned by American critics for being too modern. Despite criticism, Weber exhibited his work extensively in the 1910s, and also began creating abstract sculptures. In 1914 he helped his friend Clarence H. White open the White School of Photography and taught art history there for four years. Also in 1914 his Cubist Poems were published in London. His second book of poetry Primitives was published in 1926.
In 1916 Weber married Frances Abrams. He began to explore narrative subjects in his paintings and in 1918 began carving woodblock prints. He also taught at the Art Students League for the 1919-1921 and 1926-1927 sessions. By the early 1920s he was recognized as an important American artist, serving as a leader in art organizations such as the Society of Independent Artists. In 1930 Weber became the first American modernist to have a retrospective exhibition at the Museum of Modern Art.
In the 1930s Weber became more active in political and socialist causes, participating in many organizations throughout the Depression and World War II. In 1937 he became the National Chairman of the American Artists' Congress. By the 1940s, his work was widely known and influenced a new generation of American painters. He continued to exhibit extensively, received many awards, such as the Temple Gold Medal at the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts, and often served on art juries. In 1955 he was elected to the National Institute of Arts and Letters and received an honorary doctorate from Brandeis University. He died in Great Neck, New York, in 1961.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of New York painter and sculptor Max Weber measure 11.3 linear feet and date from 1902-2008. The collection documents Weber's career as an artist through scattered biographical material; correspondence with artists, curators, universities, arts organizations, and others; exhibition and gallery files; personal business records; writings by Weber and others; exhibition catalogs, news clippings, and other printed material; photographs of Weber, exhibitions, and works of art; and audio and film recordings. Also included are records maintained by Joy Weber on the exhibition and sale of Weber's work after his death.
Biographical material includes biographical summaries, obituaries, award certificates, and a small amount of family memorabilia. Weber's personal and professional correspondence includes discussions of exhibitions, sales, and donations of his work, as well was requests to teach, write, or lecture. Also found is correspondence with arts organizations, clubs, and committees in which he participated. A small amount of family correspondence is also included. Artists that Weber corresponded with include George Biddle, Arthur Davies, William Gropper, Chaim Gross, Marsden Hartley, Rockwell Kent, Leon Kroll, Barnett Newman, Raphael Soyer, and William Zorach, among many others. Weber also corresponded with many art historians and critics, gallery owners, and art patrons. Joy Weber's correspondence primarily concerns the exhibition, loan, sale, and authentication of her father's artwork.
Exhibition files document various solo and group exhibitions of Weber's work. Five reels of motion picture film include footage of an exhibition at the Forum Gallery in 1975. Gallery files include correspondence, inventories, sales and loan records, gallery publications, and other documentation. Most files for exhibitions and galleries were created by Joy Weber after Max Weber's death in 1961. Personal business records include documents on sales, loans, and gifts of Max Weber's artwork; scattered financial documents; and mortgage and property records. Also found are files regarding his participation in the American Artists' Congress and art juries. Weber's writings primarily concern art theory, impressions of other artists, and social and political issues. Additionally there are notes, drafts speeches, and writings by others about Weber.
Printed material is extensive and includes exhibition publications, press releases, and two published booklets written by Weber: "Art Consciousness" and "Things." Also found are news clippings, brochures, newsletters, and publications produced by art organizations, schools, and museums. Photographs include portraits and snapshots of Weber, depicting him working in his studio, participating in art juries, at art openings, and with his family. Photographs also depict installation views of exhibitions and numerous photographs of Weber's artwork. Audiovisual materials include one sound recording of a National Gallery program on Max Weber and five reels of motion picture film that include footage of an exhibition at the Forum Gallery in 1975.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 9 series:
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1905-1995 (Box 1; 10 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1902-2007 (Box 1-5; 4.2 linear feet)
Series 3: Exhibition Files, 1919-2003 (Box 5-6; 0.7 linear feet)
Series 4: Gallery Files, 1926-2005 (Box 6-7; 0.9 linear feet)
Series 5: Personal Business Records, 1906-2006 (Box 7; 0.8 linear feet)
Series 6: Writings, circa 1910s-1999 (Box 7-8; 0.6 linear feet)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1909-2008 (Box 8-10, 12; 2.6 linear feet)
Series 8: Photographs, 1930s-circa 2000 (Box 10-11; 1.1 linear feet)
Series 9: Audiovisual Material, 1954-2000 (Box 11; 3 folders)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Forum Gallery (New York, N.Y.); American Artists' Congress
Subjects-Topical:
Art, American; Artists' studios--Photographs; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Painting, American; Sculptors--New York (State)--New York
Types of Materials:
Motion pictures (visual works); Photographs; Sound recordings
Names:
Biddle, George, 1885-; Davies, Arthur B. (Arthur Bowen), 1862-1928; Gropper, William, 1897-; Gross, Chaim, 1904-1991; Hartley, Marsden, 1877-1943; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971; Kroll, Leon, 1884-1974; Newman, Barnett, 1905-1970; Soyer, Raphael, 1899-1987; Zorach, William, 1887-1966
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Biographical Material, 1905-1995, Series 1:; (Box 1; 10 folders)
  Biographical material includes award certificates, a copy of Weber's marriage certificate and wedding announcement, Weber's obituaries, and a small amount of family memorabilia. Also found are biographical summaries, including a chronology, Who's Who articles, and a biographical summary written by art historian Percy North. Also of interest is a list of public and private art collections containing works by Weber. Notes for an interview appear to have been written by Joy Weber in preparation for an interview about her father.
  - Awards, circa 1941-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Summaries, circa 1926-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Collections Containing Works by Weber, 1940s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Family Memorabilia, 1905-1923 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Identification Cards, circa 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Marriage Certificate, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notes for Interview, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Obituaries, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Papers at Archives of American Art, circa 1960s-1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Wedding Announcement, 1916 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, 1902-2007, Series 2:; (Box 1-5; 4.2 linear feet)
  The series is arranged as 2 subseries:
  2.1: Max Weber Correspondence, 1902-1969
  2.2: Joy Weber Correspondence, 1960-2007
  - Max Weber Correspondence, 1902-1969, 2.1:
    Found here is Max Weber's personal and professional correspondence, the bulk of which dates from 1915 to 1961. There is correspondence with many fellow artists, including artists he met in his travels and participation in art organizations and committees. There is also correspondence with students and publishers, requests for him to teach, lecture, or write, and business correspondence regarding exhibitions, sales, and donations. There are also a few early letters written by Weber to his parents and letters written to his wife, Frances, and his children.
    Artists that Weber corresponded with include George Biddle, Alvin Coburn, Arthur Davies, Marius de Zayas, Katherine Dreier, William Gropper, Chaim Gross, Marsden Hartley, Zoltan Hecht, Milton Horn, Rockwell Kent, Leon Kroll, Barnett Newman, Raphael Soyer, and William Zorach, among many others. Weber also corresponded with many art historians and critics, curators, and gallery owners, such as Frank Crowninshield, Emily Genauer, J. B. Neumann, and Harry Salpeter, as well as art patrons Mabel Dodge, Milton and Edith Lowenthal, and Linda Miller.
    Also found is correspondence with arts organizations, clubs, and committees in which he participated. This includes the American Federation of Arts, Artists Equity Association, Art in Federal Buildings, Municipal Art Committee of New York, and the National Institute of Arts and Letters, among many others. These files may contain copies of letters between other members as well as printed material sent out to members. Weber also corresponded with schools, galleries, and museums, primarily regarding his participation in events and exhibitions. Also of note is correspondence and invitations regarding the 1945 inauguration of Franklin Roosevelt and the inauguration of John F. Kennedy.
    In general, letters are filed alphabetically by person or corporate name. Names with five or more letters are filed in their own folders, and the remainder of correspondence is filed in miscellaneous alphabetical files. Selected correspondents whose names do not appear in headings are indicated in a note following the folder heading. Some correspondence with individuals may also be filed according to the name of the organization with which they were associated. Where they exist, drafts of Weber's outgoing letters are interfiled with incoming letters.
    - Letters to Parents, 1902, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Letters to Frances Weber and Family, 1915, 1918-1924 (Box 1, Folder 12-23)
    - Letters to Frances Weber and Family, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 24-35)
    - Letters to Frances Weber and Family, 1929-1954 (Box 1, Folder 36-42)
    - Letters to Frances Weber and Family - Undated, circa 1915-1933 (Box 1, Folder 43-44)
    - Letters to Max Weber from Family, 1917-1953 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - A.C.A. Gallery, circa 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Abbott, Jere (Smith College Museum of Art), 1940 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Albright Art Gallery, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - American Art Research Council, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - American Artists School, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - American Federation of Arts, 1939-1960 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - American Fund for Palestinian Institutions, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1925-1946 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - American-Israel Cultural Foundation, 1959-1966 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - American Society of Painters, Sculptors, and Gravers, 1930-1938 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Archives of American Art, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Art in Federal Buildings, Inc. (Forbes Watson), 1940-1942 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Art Institute of Chicago, 1928-1954 (Box 1, Folder 59-60)
    - Art Students League of New York, 1919-1947, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Artists Equity Association, 1947-1955 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - A, Miscellaneous, 1917-1962 (Box 1, Folder 63-65)
      (Includes letters from American Artists Group and John Taylor Arms)
    - Bahr, A. W., 1948, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Baltimore Museum of Art, 1941-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ben-Zion, circa 1949-1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bernheim Jeune et Cie, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Biddle, George, circa 1949-1961 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Boston Public Library, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Brandeis University, 1955-1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Brooklyn Museum, 1939-1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - B, Miscellaneous, 1918-1968 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
      (Includes letters from Louis Bouche, Peter Bunnell, and Paul Burlin)
    - Carnegie Institute, 1923-1951 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    - City of New York Municipal Art Committee, 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Coburn, Alvin, circa 1916-1936 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - College Art Association, 1932-1939 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Columbia University, 1937-1938, 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1932-1956 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Crowninshield, Frank, 1915-1934 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - C, Miscellaneous, 1910-1962 (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Dance International, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Davidson, Israel, 1936-1941 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Davies, Arthur, circa 1913-1915 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Davis, Aaron W., 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Davis, Helen M., 1935-1960 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - De Casseres, Benjamin, circa 1915-1926 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - de Zayas, Marius, 1919, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
    - Dirk, Nathaniel, circa 1915-1946 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Dodge, Mabel, circa 1910s (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Dreier, Katherine (Societe Anonyme), 1920-1931 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Dunoyer de Segonzac, Andre, 1950-1963 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - D, Miscellaneous, 1906-1956 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      (Includes letters from Jo Davidson, Stuart Davis, Terry Dintenfass, and Arthur Dove)
    - E. W. Bohannon Scholarship Fund, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - E, Miscellaneous, 1915-1961 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      (Includes letters from Ehrich Galleries and Phillip Evergood)
    - Federal Arts Committee, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Fine Arts Foundation, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Fitzpatrick, D. R., 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Ford, Alice, circa 1944-1961 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Furlong, Thomas, 1932-1951 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - F, Miscellaneous, 1934-1961 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - George Eastman House, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Genauer, Emily, 1947-1955 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Golden Gate International Exposition, 1938-1940 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Grierson, Francis, 1916-1918 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Gropper, William, circa 1936-1949 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Gross, Chaim, circa 1950-1973 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - G, Miscellaneous, 1915-1958 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      (Includes letters from William Glackens, Arshile Gorky, Lena Gurr, and Robert Gwathmey)
    - Halpert, Sam, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Harris, Tudor, 1927, 1931-1946 (Box 2, Folder 51-53)
    - Hartley, Marsden, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Hecht, Zoltan, 1916-1949 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Heydenryk, H., 1947-1959 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - High School of Music and Art, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Hoppe, E. O., 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Horn, Milton and Estelle, 1945-1954 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Hubbard, Marjorie, 1943-1952 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - H, Miscellaneous, 1909-1959 (Box 2, Folder 61)
      (Includes letters from Robert Henri and Stefan Hirsch)
    - I, Miscellaneous, 1923-1962 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Jewish Museum, 1947-1958 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Jewish Survey, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, circa 1933-1956 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - J, Miscellaneous, circa 1933-1960 (Box 2, Folder 67)
      (Includes draft letters to Edward Alden Jewell)
    - Kennedy, John F., Inauguration, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Kent, Rockwell, 1937-1956 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Kroll, Leon, circa 1919-1947 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - K, Miscellaneous, circa 1915-1956 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Little Man Press, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Lowenthal, Milton and Edith, circa 1944-1959 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - L, Miscellaneous, circa 1905-1957 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      (Includes letters from Isabel Lachaise, Life Magazine, and Louis Lozowick)
    - Mathews, Elkin, 1914-1919 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Medical Bureau to Aid Spanish Democracy, 1937-1938 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Meixner, Mary, circa 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Menorah Journal, 1925-1941 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Merrill, Thomas D., 1907-1916 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1934-1951 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Miller, Nathan and Linda, circa 1915-1936 (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
    - Montross Gallery, 1915-1923 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Muhlstock, Louis, 1956-1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Museum of Modern Art, circa 1930-1960 (Box 3, Folder 15-17)
    - Museum of Tel-Aviv, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - M, Miscellaneous, 1915-1961 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
      (Includes letters from the MacDowell Club, Marie Harriman, and a draft letter to Henri Matisse)
    - National Council of American Soviet Friendship, 1942-1949 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Neumann, J. B., 1924-1942 (Box 3, Folder 23-25)
    - Newark Museum, 1928-1961 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Newman, Barnett, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - New York World's Fair, 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - North Shore Child Guidance Association, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - N, Miscellaneous, circa 1922-1964 (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
    - O'Keeffe, Georgia (Photocopies), 1926-1958 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - O, Miscellaneous, 1910-1958 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Paul Rosenberg & Co., 1942-1954 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Pearson, Ralph M., 1939-1948 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Pennsylvania Museum of Art, 1934, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Pitt & Scott, Ltd., 1913-1923 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Portland Art Museum, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Pratt Institute, 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Public Use of Art Committee, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - P, Miscellaneous, 1908-1961 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      (Includes letters from Walter Pach, Waldo Peirce, and George Picken)
    - Reichman, Fred, 1953-1959 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., circa 1937-1961 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., Inauguration, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Russian War Relief, Inc., 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Q-R, Miscellaneous, 1917-1962 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      (Includes letters from Walter Quirt and Diego Rivera)
    - Salaman (Lowy), Gertrude, 1916-1929 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Salpeter, Harry, 1938-1960 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Sarkar, Benoy Kumar, 1915-1953 (Box 3, Folder 49-50)
    - Scholastic Awards, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Schulte, Antoinette, 1949-1963 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Segal, Samuel M., circa 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Skowhegan School of Painting and Sculpture, circa 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Soyer, Raphael, 1953-1960 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Spanish Intellectual Aid, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Spingold, Nate and Frances, 1955-1958 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - State University of Iowa, 1948-1958 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - S, Miscellaneous, 1906-1961 (Box 3, Folder 59-61)
      (Includes letters from Paul Sachs, John Sloan, Society of Independent Artists, and Maurice Sterne)
    - Tucker, Richard, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - T, Miscellaneous, circa 1918-1949 (Box 3, Folder 63)
      (Includes letters from the Treasury Department, Procurement Division)
    - United American Artists, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - University of Georgia, 1957-1959 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - University of Minnesota, 1948-1957 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - U, Miscellaneous, 1937-1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Van Noppen, Leonard and Adah, 1911-1943 (Box 4, Folder 2-6)
    - Van Noppen, Leonard and Adah - Photographs Included with Letters, circa 1911-1940s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Von Kuirim, Anna, 1908-1909 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - V, Miscellaneous, 1937-1959 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Wadsworth Atheneum, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Walker Art Center, circa 1946-1949 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Wallace for President, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Warner, Keith, circa 1944-1947 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Washburn College, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Weichsel, John, 1915-1917 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1932-1959 (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
    - William Rockhill Nelson Gallery of Art, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Worcester Art Museum, 1933-1945 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Works Progress Administration (Federal Art Project), 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - W, Miscellaneous, 1917-1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      (Includes a postcard from Abraham Walkowitz and a letter from Harold Weston)
    - Young, Art, 1937-1943 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Zorach, William, 1930-1969 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
    - Y-Z, Miscellaneous, 1938-1961 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Letters in Yiddish (Unidentified), circa 1920s (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Unidentified Correspondence, circa 1916-1958 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Joy Weber Correspondence, 1960-2007, 2.2:
    Joy Weber's correspondence primarily concerns the exhibition, loan, sale, and authentication of her father's artwork. Correspondence is with art historians, collectors, museums, galleries, universities, and students. Also found are a few condolence letters addressed to Joy and her mother, Frances, after Weber's death. Joy Weber maintained both alphabetical and chronological files of correspondence. Files are arranged alphabetically by name of person or organization followed by general correspondence arranged chronologically. Researchers should note that additional correspondence can be found in Series 3: Exhibition Files and Series 4: Gallery Files.